Manfred Joa

Full Stack Software Developer

(718) 362-0081 · New York, NY · Email · Portfolio · LinkedIn · GitHub

Profile

A Full Stack Software Developer with 5 years experience in high-level retail management, customer service, and operations. A natural leader driven by the belief in leading by example and instilling a goal-oriented work ethic and big-results mindset, achieved through development of teams and fostering of collaborative and open environments conducive to inspiring passion and creative problem solving. Excellent attention to detail, leadership, adaptability, empathy, and communication and listening abilities make an asset not just to any company, but its clients as well.

Skills

Front-End Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Canvas, Redux, TailwindCSS, Material Tailwind **Back-End Technologies:** Node.js, Python, Express, Flask, Django, JWT (JSON Web Token) Authentication **API Design and Development:** designing and building RESTful APIs, Postman, DRF (Django REST Framework) **Database Management:** MongoDB, Mongoose, PostgreSQL, Peewee

Version Control: Git. GitHub. Git Workflows

Software Development Projects

June 2023 - September 2023

You & Meme - GitHub Client Repository | GitHub Server Repository | Deployed App

- Led a team of 5 other developers to deploy a DR (Django, React) stack social media application in 1 week by delegating roles and offering debugging support to ensure coding best practices were implemented successfully
- Integrated an API while also creating an API and designing a custom user model with a one-to-one relationship with the Django User model, to render a responsive and efficient user experience with posts, comments, and likes

Wine About It - GitHub Client Repository | GitHub Server Repository | Deployed App

- Collaborated with team of 3 other developers as Code Owner to deploy a MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) stack ecommerce application in 1 week by deploying with Heroku and Netlify, while resolving merge conflicts
- Implemented styling, user registration, sign-in, favorites, and cart features by utilizing React, TailwindCSS, Material Tailwind, Redux, JWT Authentication, and local storage to enable storage and manipulation of user data

Hangman - GitHub Repository | Deployed App

- Coded game logic utilizing HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Canvas, and DOM manipulation to design a front-end game
- Tested game without referencing code online by utilizing the terminal console and logs to identify sources of errors and debug accordingly to ensure usability and correct rendering of win/lose scenarios and drawing of hangman

Professional Experience

General Assembly, Software Engineering Fellow

June 2023 - September 2023

• Building competency in full-stack web development through a three month immersive dedicated to prepare students to think like engineers and approach problems in order to build the next generation of web applications

Michaels Stores, Assistant Store Manager | Framing Manager

Aug 2019 - June 2023

- Executed daily operations and company initiatives through management of department managers, delegation, project management, and development of a collaborative team through cross training from multiple departments
- Created weekly store schedule using 600+ budgeted hours to establish full coverage, while managing payroll daily
- Exceeded custom framing sales goals during COVID, +30% Q4 2020 and FY 2022 +6% vs. company -2% by analyzing store sales performance metrics/KPIs to develop goal-oriented action plans to improve sales and business acumen
- Prioritized developing customer relationships through personable customer service to create brand loyalty and utilized top-down selling techniques in selling value, resulting in store AUR \$150 vs. company AUR \$120

Education

General Assembly

Software Engineering Immersive

SUNY Purchase College

New York, New York June 2023 - September 2023

Purchase, New York

Bachelor of Arts in Arts Management, Magna Cum Laude